[{"question":"<p><strong>A man and wife went to buy an article costing N400. The woman had 10% of the cost and the man 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N216","N200","N184","N144"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Add the same number to the numerator and denominator of <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>18<\/sub>. If the resulting fraction is &frac12;, then the number added is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["13","14","15","12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>After getting a rise of 15%, a man&rsquo;s new monthly salary is <span style=\"text-decoration: line-through;\">N<\/span>345 How much per month did he earn before the increase?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N330","N96.75","N300","N293.25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Assuming <em>log<\/em><sub>e<\/sub> 4.4 = 1.4816&nbsp; and&nbsp; <em>log<\/em><em><sub>e<\/sub><\/em> 7.7 = 2.0142, then the value of <em>log<\/em><sub>e<\/sub>&nbsp; (7\/4) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.5326","3.4958","0.4816","0.0142"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express 130 kilometres per second in metres per hour.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7.8 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>","468 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>","7,800,000","4.68 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a circular paper disc is trimmed in such a way that its circumference is reduced in the ratio 2:5, in what ratio is the area reduced?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8:125","2:5","8:25","4:25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In base ten, the number 101101 (base 2) equals<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","4","45","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The annual profits of a transport business were divided between the two partners A and B&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>in the ratio 3:5.&nbsp; If B receives <span style=\"text-decoration: line-through;\">N<\/span>3,000 more than A, the total profit was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N5,000","N1,800","N12,000","N24,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The diameter of a metal rod is measured as 23.40cm to four significant figures. What is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>the maximum error in the measurement?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.05cm","0.5cm","0.045cm","0.005cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ratio of the price of a loaf of bread to the price of a packet of sugar in 1975 was <em>r<\/em> :<em>t<\/em>, in 1980 the price of a loaf went up by 25% and that of a packet of sugar by 10%. Their new ratio is now<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40r:50t","44r:50t","50r:44t","55r:44t"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two distinct sectors in the same circle subtend 100<sup>0<\/sup> and 30<sup>0<\/sup> respectively at the centre of the circle. Their corresponding arcs are in the ratio<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1:100","3:1","5:2","10:3"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the number whose logarithm to base 10 is 2.3482?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["223.6","0.2228","2.235","0.02229"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a dealer sells a bicycle for <span style=\"text-decoration: line-through;\">N<\/span>81 he makes a profit of 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N73","N74.52","N75","N75.52"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write the decimal number 39 to base 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100111","110111","111001","100101"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A father is now three times as old as his son. Twelve years ago, he was six times as old as&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>his son. How old are the son and the father?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20 and 45","100 and 150","45 and 65","20 and 60"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the principal which amount to =N= 4,400 at simple interest in 5years at 2% per annum.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["=N=3,800","=N=5.200","=N=5,000","=N=4,000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Robson bought bags of orange for =N=2,500 each. He sold them for =N=90,000 at a loss of 20%. How many bags of orange did he buy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","80","50","45"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The second and fifth terms of a geomet ic p og ession are 21 and 567 respectively find the first term and the common ratio of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3, 7","7, 3","-7, 3","-3, 7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Tunse bought a house for =N=1,250,000 and spent =N=350,000.00 to renovate it. He then sold the house for =N=2,000,000.00. What is the percentage gain?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40%","65%","35%","25%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>List the integral values of which satisfy the inequality -2 &lt; 7 &ndash; 3x = 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-1, 0, 1, 2","-2, 0, 1","1, 2, 3","0, 1,2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The lengths of the sides of a right angled triangle are ym, (3y &ndash; 1)m and (3y + 1)m, find y.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12","9","8","4"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three students share a bag of garri in such a way that the first student took&frac14; of the garri and the second&frac34; of the remainder What fraction of the bag of garri did the third student take?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/16","2\/9","3\/5","4\/15"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x + 1 is a factor of x<sup>3<\/sup> + 3x<sup>2<\/sup> + Kx + 4, find the value of K.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","4","-4","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Paul and his friend, Peter went to buy an article costing =N=600. Peter had 10% of the cost and the Paul 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether<\/strong><\/p>","options":["=N=320","=N=440","=N=276","=N=196"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the number of sides of a regular polygon whose interior angle is twice the exterior angle.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","6","8","9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of p, if the line which passes through (-1, -p) and (-2p, 2) is parallel to the line 2y + 8x&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>&ndash; 17 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6\/7","4\/7","2\/5","\u00966\/7"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Obtain a maximum value of the function f(x) = x<sup>3<\/sup> - 12x + 11<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-15","27","15","20"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y = 5cos (-6x), dy\/dx is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30sin (-6x)","5sin (-6x)","-30sin (-6x)","-30cos (-6x)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the variance of the numbers k, k + 1, k + 2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/3","3","2\/3","1"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what value of x is the function y = x2 - 6x - 7 minimum<br \/><\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","5","6","2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x and y represent the mean and the median respectively of the following marks of students in a Mathematics test 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 21. Find x\/y correct to 1 decimal places.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.0","3.0","5.0","2.0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line through (5, 7) parallel to the line 7x + 5y &ndash; 5 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5y + 7x= 70","7x + 5y= 7","5x + 7y= 110","y + 5x= 70"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the distance between points A(-4, 5) and B(-3, 2)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","2?5","3","?10"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Rationalize (4&radic;7 + &radic;2)\/(&radic;2 - &radic;7)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-?14 - 6","2?14 - 6","-3?14 - 28","?14 - 8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A housewife bought five yams at Y34 per yam and three oranges at Y5 each where Y is the currency reckoned in base six. The total amount spent by the housewife is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Y225<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y252<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y315<sub> 6<\/sub>","Y352<sub> 6<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Divide the L.C.M. of 36, 54 and 90 by their HCF<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","20","18","45"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The number 327,036 was corrected to 327,000. Which of the following can exactly describe the degree of approximation used?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>I. to 3 significant figures <\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>II. to&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><strong><em>4 significant figures<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>III&nbsp; to the nearest hundred&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <\/em><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><em>IV&nbsp;<\/em><\/strong><strong><em>to the nearest thousand<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["I and III only","I and IV only","I, II and III only","I, II, III and IV"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of x if 4logx + 5logx &ndash; 7logx = log16<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","8","16"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A motorist drives from P to Q at an average speed of 80 km\/hr and immediately returns from Q to P through the same route at an average speed of 50km\/hr. The average speed for the round-trip journey is<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["53.3 km\/hr","60.0 km\/hr","61.5 km\/hr","65.0 km\/hr"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>X sold a radio set to Y at profit of 10% and Y sold it for =N=2, 612.50 at a loss of 5%. The&nbsp;cost of the radio to X was<\/strong><\/p>","options":["=N=2,500","=N=2,488","=N=2,375","=N=2,272"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The minimum point on the curve y = x<sup>2<\/sup> &ndash; 4x + 3 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2, -1)","(0, 3)","(1, 0)","(2, -4)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>There are 8 green ball, 4 blue balls and 3 white balls in a box. Then 1 greenand 1 blue balls are taken from the box and put away. What is&nbsp; the probability that a blue ball is selected at random from the box?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/13","2\/13","4\/15","3\/15"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A student measures a piece of rope and found it was 127m long. If the actual length of the rope was 125m, what waas the percentage error in the measurement ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.6%","1.0%","0.8%","0.16%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>At what rate will the interest on N500 increase to N25 in 5 years reckoning&nbsp; in simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2 %","1%","4%","5%"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The 3rd term of an arithmetic progression is 8 and the 7th term is -28. Find the 10th term of the progression.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-43","-164","164","44"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x *y= x-y<sup>2<\/sup>, find the value of (2*3)*5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-25","25","-32","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Five years ago, a father was 3 times as old as his son. Now, their combined ages amount to 110 years. Thus, the present age of the father is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["75 years","60 years","98 years","80 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mother reduced the quantity of food bought for the family by 10% when she found that the cost of living had increased by 15%. Thus the fractional increase in the family food bill is now<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/12","6\/35","19\/300","7\/200"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a soccer competition in one season, a club had scored the following goals: 2,0,3,3,2,1,4,0,0,5,1,0,2,2,1,3,1,4,1, and 1. The mean, median and mode are respectively.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1,1.8,and1.5","1.8,1.5 and 1","1.8,1 and 1.5","1.5, 1 and 1.8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two triangles have the same area if&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Two sides in one triangle are equal to two sides in the other.","Three sides in one triangle are equal to three sides in the other.","Two angles in one triangle are equal to two angles in the other.","Three angles in one triangle are equal to three angles inn the other."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 25x-1 = 64 (5\/2)<sup>6<\/sup>, then x has the value<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7","4","32","5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The smallest number such that when it is divided by 8 has a remainder of 6 and when it is divided by 9 has a remainder of 7 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["50","70","80","60"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a dealer sells a bicycle for N81 he makes profitof 8%. What did he pay for the bicycle ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N74","N74.52","N75","N75.52"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man and his wife went to buy article costing N400. The woman had 10% of the cost and the man 40% of the remainder. How much did they have altogether.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N216","N200","N184","N144"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a school there are 35 students in class 2A and 40 in 2B. The mean score for class 2A in a Mathematics examination is 60.00 and that for 2B in the paper is 52.5. Find, to one place of decimals, the mean of the combined classes.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["56.5","56.0","56.3","56.2"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A set of data contains a total of 130 items which are divided into six groups for display on a pie chart. If one of the groups contains 26 items then the sector representing this group on the pie chart contains an angle x at the centre of the circle where x is <\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","60","70","72"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A pentagon has four of its angles equal. If the size of the fifth angle is 60<sup>0<\/sup>&nbsp;find the size of each of the four equal angles.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60<sup>0<\/sup>","108<sup>0<\/sup>","120<sup>0<\/sup>","150<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What will be the value of k so that the equation Kx<sup>2<\/sup> - 4x+1=0 has equal roots ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","4","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x varies inversely as y, and y varies directly as the square root of z, and z varies directly as 1\/w<sup>2<\/sup>, write down in words how x varies with w.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x varies inversely as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w<sup>-1<\/sup>","x varies directly as w","x varies inversely as w"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contain 3 apples, r oranges and 3 bananas. What is the probability&nbsp; of selecting a banana and then an apple ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9\/100","9\/10","1\/10","2\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can a committe of 3 women and 4 men be chosen from 6 men and 5 women<\/strong><\/p>","options":["250","25","50","100"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write down the number 0.0052048 correct to three significant figures.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.005","0.0052","0.00521","0.00520"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Write the decimal number 39 to base 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["110111","100111","111000","110111"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An open rectangular box externally measures 4m x 3m x4m. Find the costs of painting the box eternally if its cost #2.00 to paint one square metre<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N11 6.0","N11 3.00","N11 2.00","#13 6.00"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If Musa scored 75 in Biology instead of 57, his average mark in four subjects would have been 60. What was his total mark ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["200","222","322","122"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sola deposited #150.00 in the bank. At the end of 5 years, the simple interest on the princinpal was #55.00. At what rate per annum was the interest paid ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.3 3%","8.3 3%","7.32%","7.33%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the 20 terms in an arithmetic progression whose first term is&nbsp; 7 and the last term is 117<\/strong><\/p>","options":["239","1240","1340","1440"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The range of the data k+2,k-3,k+,k-2,k-5,k+3,k-1 and k+6 is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","11","12","13"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area bounded by the curve y =x (2 - x), the x-axis, x=0 and x=2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.25sq.units","133sq.units","0.33sq.units","2.33sq.units"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A trader realizes 10x-X<sup>2<\/sup>naira profit from the salae of x bags of corn. How many bags will give him the maximum profit ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","4","3","5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cinema hall contains a certain number&nbsp; of people. If 22.5% are children 47.5% are men and 84 are women, find the number of men in the hall.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["133","132","130","123"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An arc of a circle subtends an angle of 30 on the circumference of a circle of radius 21cm. Find the length of the arc.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11cm","22cm","66cm","44cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of a set of six numbers is 60. If the mean of the first five is 50, find the sixth number in the set.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100","120","105","110"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of the interior angles of a regular polygon is 1800<sup>0<\/sup>. Calculate the size of one exterior angle of the polygon.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["45<sup>-1<\/sup>","60<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","90<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the simple interest rate percent per annum at which #1,000 accumulates to #1,240 in 3 years.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8%","7%","6%","5%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man invested #5000 for 9 months at 4%. What is the simple interest ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N220","N130","N150","N250"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If log<sub>3<\/sub>18+log<sub>3<\/sub>3-log<sub>3<\/sub>x&nbsp;= 3, find x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","0","3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Raila has 7 different posters to be hanged in her bedroom, living room, and kitchen. Assuming she has plans to replace at least a poster in each of the 3 rooms, how many choices does she have?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["49","170","210","21"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the sum of the first 18 terms of the series 3,6,9,....,36<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513","505","433","635"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The second term of a geometrics series is 4 while the fourth term is 16. Find the sum of the first five terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60","54","64","62"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the size of each interior angle of a 12-sided regular polygon ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["120<sup>-1<\/sup>","150<sup>-1<\/sup>","30<sup>-1<\/sup>","180<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A circle of perimeter 28cm is opened to form a square. What is the maximum possible area of the square ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["56cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","98cm<sup>-1<\/sup>","49cm<sup>-1<\/sup>","28cm<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A solid metal cube of side 3cm is placed in a rectangular tank of dimensions 3, 4 and&nbsp; 5cm. What volume of water can the tank now&nbsp; hold<\/strong><\/p>","options":["48cm","33cm<sup>3<\/sup>","60cm<sup>3<\/sup>","27cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perpendicular bisector of a line XY is the locus of a point<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Whose distance from X is always twice its distance from Y","Whose distance from Y is always twice its distance from X","Which moves on the line XY","Which is equidistance from the points X and Y"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The midpoint of P (x,y) and Q (8,6) is (5,8). Find x and y.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(2,10)","(2,8)","(2,12)","(2,6)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man walks 100m due West from a point X to Y,he then walks 100m due North to a point Z. Find the bearing of X from Z.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["195<sup>-1<\/sup>","135<sup>-1<\/sup>","225<sup>-1<\/sup>","045<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The derivative of (2x+1)(3x+1) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["12x+1","6x+5","6x+1","12x+5"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sum of four consecutive integers is 34. Find the least of these numbers.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","8","7","5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The nth term of a sequence is n<sup>2<\/sup> - 6n-4. Find the sum of the 3rd and 4th terms.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["24","23","-24","-25"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The binary operation is defined on the set of integers such that&nbsp;<em>p*q&nbsp;= pq+p-q.&nbsp;<\/em>Find 2*(3*4).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","13","15","22"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A circular arc subtend angle 150<em><sup>o<\/sup><\/em> at the centre of a circle&nbsp; of radius 12cm. Calculate&nbsp; the area of the sec to r of the arc.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","60cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","120cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>","150cm2<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the volume of a cuboid of length 0.76cm,&nbsp; breadth 2.6 cm and height 0.82cm.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.92cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","2.13cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.97cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>","1.62cm3<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man stands on a tree 150cm high and see a boat an angle of depression of 74<sup>0<\/sup>. Find the distance of the boat from the base of the tree.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["52cm","43cm","40cm","15cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of seven numbers is 96. If the eight number is added, athe mean becomes 112. Find the eight number.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["126","180","216","224"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the median of 2,3,7,3,4,5,8,9,9,4,5,3,4,2 and 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9","8","7","4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the standard deviation of 2,3,8, 10 and 12.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.9","4.9","5.9","6.9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can the letters of the word TOTALITY be arranged ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6720","6270","6207","6027"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a bag, there are 8 identical balls in terms of size and shape, but 2 are white, 4 are black and 2 are yellow. If<\/strong><br \/><strong>balls are randomly drawn from the bag without<\/strong><br \/><strong>replacement, what is the probability that two cells drawn<\/strong><br \/><strong>from the bag, one is white and yellow and the other black?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/7","6\/7","5\/7","1\/7"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the roots of the equation 6x<sup>2<\/sup>&nbsp;- 13x + 6 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2\/3, 3\/2","2\/3, -3\/2","-2\/3, -3\/2","2\/3, 3\/2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A polynomial in x whose zeros are 2, -1 and -7 is x2+6x2+9x14bx3 &ndash; 6x2+14cx3+6x2 &ndash; 9x14 dx3 &ndash; 6x2 &ndash; 9x+14 6. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If y = (91-3x)3. find the value of dy at dx2. x = -2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["378","-441","-378","441"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If y = (1-3x)<sup>3<\/sup>. find the value of dy\/dx at x = -2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["378","-324","-378","441"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 366 base ten to a binary number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["101110010","-101101110","10110111","-1011000"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that x = 3, y = -2 and z = -1. Evaluate 3x<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>2<\/sup>zx<sup>2<\/sup>y<sup>3<\/sup>z<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6776","9787","-7776","-9776"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two ships A and B left port P on a bearings 0530 and<\/strong><br \/><strong>1130 respectively. If both ships steamed at 80km per<\/strong><br \/><strong>hour, how far apart were they after 30 minutes?<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".-80km","60km","20km","40km"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What are the coordinated of the midpoint of the line<\/strong><br \/><strong>joining (-1, 6) and (5, -3)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(3, 4.5)","(2, 1.5)","(-3, 4.5)","(-2 ,- 1.5)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Determine <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">2.813 x 1.063<\/span>&nbsp;&nbsp;x 10<sup>-1<\/sup>&nbsp;reducing each number to 2 s.f and leaving the answer in 2s.f.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 5.637&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.54","0.0054","0.0056","0.055"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the inequality 2-x &gt; x<sup>2<\/sup>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x < 1 or x < -2","x > 2 or x < -1","x < -2 or x > 1","x > 2 or x < -2"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the minimum value of the function f(0)= 2 ,for 0= 0<\/strong><br \/><strong>=2 3-CosO<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2",".2\/3","2","1"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A fair coin is tossed ten times. What is the probability of getting at least two heads?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["513\/1024","615\/1024","968\/1024","1011\/1024"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man bought 220 mangoes at #5x. He sold each for 3x kobo and made a gain of #8. Find the value of x.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","5","10","6"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the sum to infinity of 1 + 1\/3&bull;}1\/9-1\/27+<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.33","0.67","1.5","2,5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Express tan 22 1 \/2, in the sun! form<\/strong><\/p>","options":["+ v2-2","l-v2","+v2-1",".+v2+l"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If sin (x-a)=Cos (x+a), then tans is<\/strong><\/p>","options":[".0.8","0.75","1.0","2.8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A binary operation x is defined on R, the set of real numbers by xy = vxy, for all x,y E R. If x*(2*8)=6, find<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","4","9","10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The equation 2x2 + (k + 3) x + 2k = 0 has co-incident<\/strong><br \/><strong>roots. What is the constant k7<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3 or 7","4 or 0","9 or l","9 or l"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The curve y =2x* + x-2 and the straight line y-2x-1<\/strong><br \/><strong>meet at the points whose x-values are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/2andl","2andl","1\/2andl","2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 5, 8, 3,7and 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","2","5","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sequence &lsquo;a, -&lsquo;I., &lsquo;I -1\/256 has a terms. Determine<\/strong><br \/><strong>the value of n<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","7","8","9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The volume of two similar solid cubes are729cm3 and<\/strong><br \/><strong>5 12cm3. Find the ratio of their lengths<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4:3","9:7","9:7","9:8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In fig C, PR is a diameter, &lt;PRQ=(3x-8), and&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>&lt;RPQ=(2y-7), Express x in terms of y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x= 75+ 2y","x= 105 + 3y","x= 105-2y","x = 75- 3y"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the mean deviation of 6,7,8,9, 10<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.2","1.5","2","8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Thematrixis2l, 34<\/strong><br \/><strong>If I is the 2x2 unit matrix, then k2 +1 + k is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6 3 1320","9 8 2223","l0 7 2124","1 4 25"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The line joining (p, 4) and (6, -2) is perpendicular to<\/strong><br \/><strong>the line joining (2,p) and (-1.3).Find p<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","3","4","0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a regular polygon, each interior angle double its<\/strong><br \/><strong>corresponding exterior angle. Find the number of sides of<\/strong><br \/><strong>the polygon<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","4","6","8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The mean of the numbers 0, x+2+, 3x+6 and4x+8 is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>4. <\/strong><strong>Find their mean deviation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","3","2","0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"}]